So I am on the AWS console, so let me just search for Lex and I am on the Lex home page.
So it says Amazon Lex a conversation AI for self-service bots and let me just click
on this create bot and you can see here there are different ways of creating a bot.
So you can create a descriptive bot builder with generative AI and then you create a blind
bot, it creates a basic bot with no pre-configured language intents and slot types.
Also choose start with an example and example bot has pre-configured languages intents and
slot types.
So it comes with an example which can help you expedite in building the bot.
Okay, then you have start with transcripts automatically generates intents from the conversation
transcripts.
Okay, now what I will do is I will create a bot with Lex and Gen AI.
Now let's say you want to build a bot for flight booking.
So maybe I'll save flight booking and description, it's an optional so I'll leave it as it is.
I will allow Amazon Lex to create the I have role that is relevant for me.
Children online privacy protection, I'll just say no, which is demo and then I will just
click on next.
I have to choose a language so I can just leave it as English US.
Then we can also have voice based chat and it basically converts the text to speech.
So I just need to provide whether I want a male voice or a female voice and I will leave
it as Daniel.
So once I've selected the voice then what I have to do is I can use the Gen AI and it
uses a foundation model called as Cloud from entropic to generate this bot for me.
So let me just give a description.
So what I said is I want to build a flight booking bot which allows to book flights with
date, source and destination location.
So you can see here we have the flight booking bot which is the intent and then we have
date, source and destination location which are the slots.
Now with this description I will allow the Gen AI model cloud V2 to build a bot using Lex
for me.
So I'll say it done.
So you can see it is still building the bot for me, generate bot local for English US.
So I just waited a few minutes and now you can see it's generating bot local for English
US succeeded so I can do a review and see what has been built.
And here you can see that it is created generated intents.
So if I just click on this and you can see for sample utterances and if you remember
we said utterances were were the input provided by the user to accomplish a goal and
the goal is to book a flight.
So if he says book a flight, book a flight from source to destination, book me a flight.
So these are all the utterances that the user can either speak or type.
And then you have the slots, we need four inputs from the user.
So departure date return date destination and source if I have to book a flight.
So I will say add to selection and then I will just confirm intents and slot types adding
generated resources.
So now if I just go here book a flight and you can see here we have the sample utterances
and then we have the slots.
So return date departure date source and destination which we need to book a flight.
Then we have the confirmation.
So once the user provides these details, then we can play back the input that user has
provided and ask him do you want to book a flight from New York to Chicago on 25th and
then return on 26th or something like that.
So under the confirmation, I can just click here and then I can just say maybe the same
thing is saying can I go ahead with the request and then we have the fulfilment which means
that your booking is confirmed.
So if I just click on active and on successful fulfilment and I will just type it, maybe
I will say your booking is confirmed, thank you and then you can also provide values in
case of failure something went wrong etc. so I will just do save intent.
Now this is complete what I can do is I will just click on build and then we will just
test it out.
So I just waited a few minutes and now it is saying successfully built English language
in bought flight booking.
So I can just click on test now and let me just say book a flight.
So it is asking me for the departure dates.
So let me just say 30th December 2025 and then it is asking me for a return date.
So I will say 15 January 2026 and it is asking me to provide the source.
So I will say Chicago and then it is asking for destination maybe New York.
So it is asking me for the confirmation can I go ahead with request and let me just say yes
and now it is saying intent book flight is fulfil.
Now if we integrate this chatbot built using legs with a backend data source maybe using
AWS Lambda function then it can take all this input that we have provided and make a entry
in the database and get a booking confirmation number.
So that is how you can build chatbots using Amazon legs.
Hope this was useful.
I will see you in the next lecture.